Joonwon Choi

Formal Verification Tech Lead at Apple
One Apple Park Way, Cupertino, CA 95014
+1-339-225-5940 | joonwonc@alum.mit.edu | http://joonwon.net/c

Current Position

Formal Verification Tech Lead, Apple

03/15/2021 - Present

I have worked on formally verifying memory subsystems and fabrics in Apple silicon. Reasoning about these components is challenging due to the numerous optimizations required to enhance system performance. My focus has been on devising methodologies to scale model checking, enabling formal reasoning at the system level, particularly for ensuring the liveness of the system.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2016 - 02/17/2021

Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2014 - 06/03/2016

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

Seoul National University

03/01/2006 - 02/26/2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Double major in Mathematical Sciences

- Graduated with honors (summa cum laude)

Selected Publications

[1] Revamping Verilog Semantics for Foundational Verification. submitted.

[2] Hemiola: A DSL and Verification Tools to Guide Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols. Joonwon Choi, Adam Chlipala, Arvind.

CAV'22 (regular paper, Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer-Aided Verification).

[3] Structural Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols.

Joonwon Choi

PhD Thesis in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.

[4] Integration Verification Across Software and Hardware for a Simple Embedded System.

Andres Erbsen, Samuel Gruetter, Joonwon Choi, Clark Wood, Adam Chlipala.

PLDI'21 (Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation).

[5] EverCrypt: A Fast, Verified, Cross-Platform Cryptographic Provider.

Jonathan Protzenko, Bryan Parno, Aymeric Fromherz, Chris Hawblitzel, Marina Polubelova, Karthikeyan Bhargavan, Benjamin Beurdouche, <u>Joonwon Choi</u>, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Natalia Kulatova, Tahina Ramananandro, Aseem Rastogi, Nikhil Swamy, Christoph M. Wintersteiger, and Santiago Zanella-Bequelin.

SP'20 (IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy).

[6] Crellvm: Verified Credible Compilation for LLVM.

Jeehoon Kang, Yoonseung Kim, Youngju Song, Juneyoung Lee, Sanghoon Park, Mark Dongyeon Shin,

Yonghyun Kim, Sungkeun Cho, <u>Joonwon Choi</u>, Chung-Kil Hur, and Kwangkeun Yi. **PLDI'18** (*Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation*).

[7] Kami: A Platform for High-Level Parametric Hardware Specification and its Modular Verification. <u>Joonwon Choi</u>, Muralidaran Vijayaraghavan, Benjamin Sherman, Adam Chlipala, Arvind. ICFP'17 (Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Functional Programming).

Working Experience

Apple, United States Formal Verification Tech Lead Senior Formal Verification Engineer Formal Verification Engineer	03/15/2021 – Current Oct 2024 – Current Oct 2023 – Sep 2024 Mar 2021 – Sep 2023
Microsoft Research Cambridge, United Kingdom Research Intern	07/02/2018 - 09/21/2018
allm Games, Korea Software Engineer (Skilled Industry Personnel as alternative military service)	04/13/2009 - 09/12/2011
Google, Korea Software Engineering Intern (SWE Intern)	01/05/2009 - 04/03/2009
Teaching Experience	
MIT 6.887: Formal Reasoning About Programs Teaching Assistant	Spring 2017

Fall 2013

Mar 2006 - Feb 2013

Academic Services

Presidential Science Scholarship

Teaching Assistent

SNU 4190.310: Programming Languages

Program Committee: VSTTE 2024, PLDI 2024, CAV 2020 AE

Honors & Awards	
Kwanjeong Educational Fellowship	Sep 2014 – May 2019
MIT Emerson Scholarship for Private Music Study	Sep 2014 – May 2018
Top Honor (summa cum laude) Certification Seoul National University	Feb 2013

Last updated: November 17, 2024